Alone in Berlin is a war, thriller, drama film directed by Vincent Perez.
Berlin in June of 1940.
While Nazi propaganda celebrates the regime’s victory over France, a
kitchen-cum-living room in Prenzlauer Berg is filled with grief.
Anna and Otto Quangel’s son has been killed at the front.
This working class couple had long believed in the ‘Führer’ and followed him willingly,
but now they realise that his promises are nothing but lies and deceit.
They begin writing postcards as a form of resistance and in a
bid to raise awareness: Stop the war machine!
Kill Hitler!
Putting their lives at risk, they distribute these cards in the
entrances of tenement buildings and in stairwells.
But the SS and the Gestapo are soon onto them, and
even their neighbours pose a threat.
Anna Quangel, played by Emma Thompson.
Otto Quangel, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Escherich, played by Daniel Brühl.
Prall, played by Mikael Persbrandt.
Claire Gehrich, played by Katharina Schüttler.
Hans Quangel, played by Louis Hofmann.
Alone in Berlin is a 2016 war drama film which was directed by
Vincent Pérez and written by Pérez and Achim von Borries.
It is based on the 1947 novel Every Man Dies Alone, by Hans Fallada.
The novel's characters Otto and Anna Quangel are based on Otto and Elise Hampel.
When their son dies in France, the couple start writing postcards to urge
people to protest against Adolf Hitler and the Nazi regime.
The film stars Emma Thompson, Brendan Gleeson,
Daniel Brühl, and Mikael Persbrandt.
Principal photography began on 27 March 2015 in Berlin.
It was selected to compete for the Golden Bear at the
66th Berlin International Film Festival.
The film explores themes of berlin, germany, based on
novel or book, world war ii, 1940s.
The tone is emotional and intense.